Guide to the Benton Sullivan Monroe papers, 1795-1963.
Monroe, Benton Sullivan papers, 1795-1963.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Benton Sullivan Monroe papers, 1795-1963.
14-12-1356
Benton Sullivan Monroe, 1873-1968.
4 cubic ft.
Correspondence, reprints, notes, student papers, scrapbooks, accounts, certificates, diplomas, and memorabilia.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Professional papers include correspondence, reprints, notes, student papers, a scrapbook concerning a Cornell Smoking Contest in which Professor Monroe was the winner, and other material related to Cornell University. Personal papers include Monroe family material; correspondence; accounts; material on Ithaca High School, Cornell University, Alpha Zeta, Town & Gown Club, and Rotary Club; certificates and diplomas; Cornell broadsides; political broadsides and memorabilia; scrapbooks; and local history material on Romulus, Varick, and Ithaca, New York.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor of English, Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Professional papers include correspondence, reprints, notes, student papers, a scrapbook concerning a Cornell Smoking Contest in which Professor Monroe was the winner, and other material related to Cornell University. Personal papers include Monroe family material; correspondence; accounts; material on Ithaca High School, Cornell University, Alpha Zeta, Town & Gown Club, and Rotary Club; certificates and diplomas; Cornell broadsides; political broadsides and memorabilia; scrapbooks; and local history material on Romulus, Varick, and Ithaca, New York.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Monroe, Benton Sullivan, 1873-1968.; Monroe family.; Alpha Zeta.; Cornell University--Faculty.; Cornell University--Students.; Ithaca High School.; Rotary Club (Ithaca, N.Y.); Town & Gown Club.
Subjects:
English language--Study and teaching.; College teachers.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Professional Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Flugel, Ewald, April 29, 1902 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Flugel, Ewald, October 26, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Emerson, O.F., January 22, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - McKnight, G.H., Ohio State U. English Dept., February 26, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Emerson, O.F., Mar. 3, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bright, James William, May 30, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Child, Clarence G., September 26, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Tatlock, John S.P., December 13, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Emerson, O.F., September 18, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Wells, John Edwin, September 19, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Spingarn, J.E., September 19, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Edlund, R.C., October 11, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Emerson, O.F. (sig. cut out), November 5, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Flugel, Ewald, November 20, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Steeves, H.R., November 29, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Andrews, Eugene P. re: his approaching marriage, February 20, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Kennedy, Charles William, July 8, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Gutstadt, M.M., manager, Lyceum Theatre, Ithaca, November 29, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Gutstadt, M.M., December 29, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Montgomery, Lois E., Wilson College, Chambersburg, Pa., October 2, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Montgomery, Lois E., December 18, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Smith, Lou; Ruthschild, Jacob; and Hickey, Joseph F.- joint invitation, Mar. 3, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Farrand, Livingston, December 2, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Ogden, Robert M., December 5, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Hull, Charles H., May 4, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Dondare (?), Dorothy, February 26, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Professional Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Coon, Arthur M., May 25, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bald, R.C., June 19, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Monroe, B.S., October 4, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Burnham, Josephine M., September 2, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Brooks, Ruth Ann Louise, September 11, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - McGuire, Ritchie, November 17, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Monroe, October 5, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Monroe, October 5, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Betten, Cornelius, November 26, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Monroe (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Eaton, Horace A., May 1, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Monroe, May 3, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Lyon, George W., September 27, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Malott, Deane W., November 4, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Willcox, Walter F., October 2, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Willcox, Walter F., September 25, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Professional Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Timmerman, Lynn D., April 23 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Willcox, Walter, reprints, 1931, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Edith Harrison, poetry, ca. 1934 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Walter French, draft, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Robert C. Fenner, talk, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Monroe - Reprints (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Alumni News Faculty Committee (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Hart on Phonology (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Gothic and Old English Philology (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Old English - Notes (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Old English Exams, 1905-1923 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Students' Essays (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Student Notebook - Old English (Box 1, Folder 11)
- American Dialect Society (Box 1, Folder 12)
- College Entrance Examination Board - Meeting (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Gould Colman - Oral History (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Cornell - Art (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Award (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Cornell - Buildings (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Cornell - Class Activities (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Cornell - Class of 1896 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Cornell - Class of 1896 - Reunions (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Cornell - Class Day (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Cornell - Ezra Cornell (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Cornell Drama Clubs - programs (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Delicate Brown (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Cornell - History (Box 1, Folder 26-27)
- Cornell - Inauguration, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Cornell - Invitations, programs (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Cornell - Lectures and forms (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Cornell - Library (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Cornell - Menu (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Cornell - Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 33-34)
- Cornell - Miscellaneous correspondence, incl. letter from John Henry Comstock to Wm. E. Sullivan, September 13, 1875 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Cornell - Music clubs - programs (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Cornell - People (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Cornell Phi Beta Kappa (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Cornell Phi Beta Kappa - Reunions (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Cornell - Presidents (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Cornell - Sage College (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Cornell Statistics, 1873, 1880 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Cornell Scrapbook, 1910-1911 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Monroe Family - Family Papers (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Monroe Family - Romulus Post Office Record (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Certificates - Monroe Family, 1887-1894 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- May Lawrence - School Papers, 1887-1894 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Addie Snyder - School Papers, 1867-1877 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Sophronia Sullivan - School Papers, 1866-1868 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Ithaca High School Class of 1890 - correspondence and miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 7)
- High School Papers, 1890-1892 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Student Essays, 1891-1894 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Latin 7 Notebook, 1894 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- "Sicyon" Archeology Notebook (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Student Notebook, 1897-1898 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Exams (Box 2, Folder 13-14)
- Alpha Eta Pi Scrapbook (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Alpha Zeta - Mss. (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Alpha Zeta (Box 2, Folder 17-18)
- Town & Gown Club - Organization (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Town & Gown Club - Events (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Ithaca Rotary Club - Notes (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Ithaca Rotary Club (Box 2, Folder 22-23)
- Ithaca Rotary Club - "Ted" Monroe Day, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Tape Recording (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Personal Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 26-27)
- Personal Correspondence - Parmelee Family (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Accounts, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Accounts, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Accounts, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Accounts, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Accounts, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Accounts, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Accounts, 1931-1933 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Personal - Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 36-37)
- World War II Ration Book (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Ithaca - Business (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Ithaca - City Government (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Ithaca High School (Box 2, Folder 41-42)
- Drawings - Dwight R. Collin - Ithaca High School, 1890 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Ithaca - Maps (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Ithaca - Manuscripts (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Ithaca - Organizations (Box 2, Folder 46-47)
- Lecture Notes (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Children's Books (Box 3, Folder 2-3)
- Regents' Pass Cards - Benton S. Monroe (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Award Cards - Nina Elson (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Ithaca High School - Photographs (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Town & Gown Club - Postcards (Box 3, Folder 7-9)
- Rotary Club Clippings (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Rotary Club Notes (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Membership Cards (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Miscellaneous invitations and calling cards (Box 4, Folder 1)
- School Awards (blank) (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Seneca County checks (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Monroe Family - Geneva, Ithaca & Sayre Railroad tickets (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Postcards (Box 4, Folder 5-6)
- Card Game Scorebooks (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Autograph Book - Mrs. David Monroe, 1876-1884 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Autograph Book - May Lawrence, 1868-1869 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Photographs (Box 4, Folder 10-11)
- Local History - Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Lincoln Assassination - clipping (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Photographs - Ithaca scenes - people (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Photographs - Cornell (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Photographs - Ithaca organizations and people (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Ithaca High School diploma - Nina Lulu Elston, 1893 (Box 4)
- NYU Academic diploma (Box 4)
- Ithaca - organizations (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Ithaca - police department (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Clippings - Cornell and Ithaca history (Box 5, Folder 3-4)
- Clippings - local history (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Dryden School District 20 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Promissory notes and letter, 1795-1796 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Romulus - Varick - Local history (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Romulus and Varick - local history - printed items (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Romulus and Seneca County - printed items (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Romulus and Varick - local history - Hunt Farm (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Diedrich Willers - documents (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Isaac Smith and contemporaries (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Dudgeon - receipts, 1869-1870 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Ovid miscellany (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Political memorabilia (Box 5, Folder 16)
- World War I and II - Posters (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Currency (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Commercial Portraits (Box 5, Folder 19)
- First Baptist Church of Romulus (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Romulus (?) Notebooks (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Scrapbook - Poe (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Scrapbook - personal (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Romulus Scrapbook (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Romulus 2 Scrapbook (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Romulus 3 Scrapbook (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Romulus Anecdotes Scrapbook (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Certificates and Diplomas (Mapcase-folder 1)
- Cornell Broadsides, Photograph (unidentified), Political Broadsides (Mapcase-folder 2)
- Romulus Broadsides (Mapcase-folder 3)